Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
集中できてないな　まだ体が迷っているんだ
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
震えていたんじゃ　コントロールしたってブレるんだ
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
ツキ
太陽も勝負運もなんも完全にこっち向いていないが
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
「やるしかないんだ」
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
言い聞かせるようにそうつぶやいた
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
状況は悪いが　ただ逃げ出すんじゃ根性ないなぁ
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
展望はないが　度胸でクリアするしかないや
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
衝動は抑えたままターゲットとの間隔探れ
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
必要なもんは勝つプライド
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
味わうのは勝利の美酒か
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
それとも敗北の苦汁か
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
そう　すべては2つに1つ
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
操りたい運命の糸
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
絶好のゴールデンタイム　この手で掴め
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
渾身のポーカーフェイス　キメて仕掛けるよ
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
イリュージョンの世界へ引きずり込んで
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
際限無いプレッシャーゲーム　スルリと抜けて
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
栄光のボーダーライン　飛び越えるために
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
ハウメニー？　どれくらいの代償がいる？
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
手放したくないもんはどれ？
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
I've got a bad feeling about this place.
気味悪い所に来ちゃったな
Father! I brought a sacrifice!
お父様人柱連れてきた
お父様っていきなり
"Father"? So suddenly...
Who is it?
誰だ
Dad?
父さん
Envy.
エンヴィー
Envy?!
This is him?!
これが
Brother!
兄さん
Al?
アル
鎧のアルってことは
Al in the armor... which means...
We were able to get back.
戻れたな
Yeah.
Brother!
兄さん
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
痛たたたっ
よかった無事だったんだね
I'm so glad to see you're safe!
That hurts, Al!
痛ぇよアル鎧の角ゴリゴリって
Your armor's hurting me!
It's just that I'm so glad to see you're alive...
だって兄さんが生きてた
You're right.
そうだよな悪ぃ
Sorry.
For worrying you.
心配掛けた
But where the heck are we?
それにしてもここはどこだ
What a surprise.
これは驚いた
Humans came out of his stomach?
腹から人間が
Hohen...heim?!
ホーエンハイム
An arm and a leg made of steel, and a suit of armor.
鋼の手足鎧
Are you the Elric Brothers?
エルリック兄弟か
It's not him?
ヤツじゃない
Are you mistaking me for somebody?
誰かと間違えてないか
Hang on...
待て
Hohen...
ホーエン
Don't tell me you're talking about Van Hohenheim?
もしかして
ヴァン·ホーエンハイムのことか
What is your relationship with him?
ヤツとはどういう関係だ
一応父親
He's... our dad.
Dad?!
父親
What a surprise! He ended up having kids?!
驚いたあいつ子供なんぞつくっておった
But aren't your last names Elric?
でも確かお前たちの姓は
エルリックではなかったか
エルリックは母方の姓だ
Elric is our mother's maiden name!
I see.
なるほどでヤツは今どこに
So, where is he now?
知らねぇよそれよりあんたの方こそ何者だ
Hell if I know!
But more importantly, who the hell are you?!
ホーエンハイムそっくりじゃねぇか
You look just like Hohenheim!
There's no way he'd die.
あれが死ぬはずがない
Listen to me!
しかし子供までつくって
And he's even had kids...
Brother, this man is...
Oh? You're injured?
ケガをしているのか
And you're missing your left arm.
そっちは左手がないな
これでいいかな
How's that?
痛っ
Ow!
A broken bone, huh?
骨折か
な治った
I-It's fixed.
Hey!
おい！
痛っ
Oww!
あとは 肋骨だな
Now for your ribs.
You two are important to us.
お前たちは大切な人材だからな
Don't be too reckless with your bodies, okay?
体は大事にせねばいかんぞ
He used alchemy without a single hand motion.
こいつなんのモーションもなしに
術を発動させた
しかも装甲を薄くせずに
And he didn't make the rest of my armor thinner, either...
In other words, it's not equivalent exchange.
つまり等価交換じゃない
Who the hell are you?
なんだ お前は
It's unreal! How could your insides be in such a state?!
ありえない
なんだ その中身は
I'm going to ask you the same exact question.
そのまま返そうなんだお前は
Who are you?
You can eat him.
食べていいぞ
はい
Okay!
ちょっちょっと待て
H-Hang on!
He's my friend!
こいつはオレの仲間だ
人柱であるオレの顔に免じて
I'm a human sacrifice, so don't kill him for my sake. Okay?
ここは ほら なっ
That's not my problem.
知ったことではない
He's useless to me.
私には必要のない人間だ
What did you say?!
なんだと
Brother, the Homunculi call him "Father".
兄さんあいつ人造人間に
「お父様」って呼ばれてる
He's the one who created them.
ヤツらをつくった張本人だよ
What?!
何
体を治してくれたけど
Even though he patched us up...
I don't like it.
気に入らないな
Your attitude...
その態度
You're the same as those who laugh at humans for being foolish.
人間を愚か者と笑うヤツらと同じだ
Do you consider insects crawling about the Earth to be foolish?
お前は地を這いずる虫を愚か者と思うか
Even if insects struggle, the difference between you and them is so great that you don't exactly give a damn.
虫ケラがあがいても
レベルが違いすぎて
なんの感慨もわかないだろう
That's precisely how I feel about you humans.
私がお前たち人間に思うのは
それと同じだ
I appreciate you healing our wounds,
but I don't think I can get along with you!
ケガは治してもらったけど
やっぱ相いれねぇ
どうやら諸悪の根源はてめぇらしいな
Seems you're the cause of everything!
I'll take care of you quickly.
一気にカタをつける
I can't be worrying about the small fry!
この際雑魚は構ってらんねぇ
雑魚とは言ってくれるね
You're calling me small fry now, runt?
おチビさん
チビ
Runt?!
I've got their leader!
親玉取ったり
Ling!
リン
What is going on?!
どうなってるんだ
How can he use alchemy without a single hand motion?!
なぜヤツは
なんのモーションもなしに錬成できる
What a waste of time.
時間の無駄だな
We can't use alchemy?!
錬金術が発動しない
Ed! Al!
エドアル
What did that geezer do?!
あのヒゲ何を
なんで
Why...
Why can't we use alchemy?!
なんで術が使えないんだ
Seriously, these tiny beings are unbelievable.
ほんとにこの下等動物どもときたら
大きな力を得た途端に浮かれやがって
They start to think they're at the top of the world as soon as they gain some power.
それがどんなものかも知らずに
They don't even know what exactly they're using.
Do you really think all this prosperity was created with the powers of humans only?
今の繁栄が自分たちの力だけで
成し遂げられたと思っているのか
How laughable, fools.
滑稽だ愚か者どもめ
What the hell are you talking about?!
どういうことだ
戻ってきたら教えるって約束だったろうが
You promised you'd tell me as soon as we got out!
What?
お前ら虫ケラとした約束なんて
I don't remember making promises with you insects.
覚えてないなぁ
てめぇ
You bastard...
You're talking too much, Envy.
しゃべりすぎだエンヴィー
はいはい
Yeah, yeah...
He could be good for the job.
素材としては悪くなさそうだな
I may be able to create another pawn.
使える駒を増やせるかもしれん
That's... a philosopher's stone!
あれは賢者の石
What?!
何っ
So you're planning to do it, huh?
あれをやる気だね
Do what?
あれ
He's creating a Homunculus.
人造人間をつくるんだよ
He's going to inject the philosopher's stone into him.
賢者の石を流し込む
If all goes well, a homunculus with a human base will be complete.
うまくいけば人間ベースの
人造人間が出来上がる
痛っ
Well, most humans end up dying because they aren't capable of fighting the stone's power.
まっ 大抵は
石の力に絶えきれず死ぬけどね
そんなことさせるか
Like I'll let you!
Let go, Envy!!
放せエンヴィー
くそどうなってんだ
Dammit, what's going on?!
なんで 術が発動しない
Why can't we use alchemy?!
てめぇこらっ
Hey, you!
ヒゲやめろ
Geezer! Stop it!
He has people waiting for his return!
そいつには待ってるヤツがいるんだよ
放せ
Let go!!!
こうすれば撃てないんだよね
Humans can't shoot me if I do this...
Right?
人間は
Damn you...
てめぇ
It's fine! Don't shoot!
いいんだ撃つな
Don't interfere.
余計なマネはするな
This is fine by me!
オレはこれでいい
What?
何
I came to this country looking for a philosopher's stone.
賢者の石を探しにこの国に来た
And he's just going to give it to me like that.
それをわざわざくれるというんだ
願ったりかなったりだ
It's exactly what I wished for!
お前何言ってんだ
What the hell are you saying?!
Oh? Sounds interesting.
ほうおもしろい
Then as you wish, it's all yours.
ならば望みどおり授けよう
やめろ
Stop it!
Ling!
リン
I... I told you not...
手手を出すなと
...to interfere!
言ったはずだ
It's fine... Just wait for me...
いいからどっしり構えてろよ
I'm the man who will become the Emperor of Xing...
オレはシンの皇帝になる男
...Ling Yao!
リン·ヤオ
What the hell is a brat doing here?!
なんでガキがこんな所にいる
Ah, well.
まあいいお前の体よこしな
Let me have your body.
オレ様が使ってやる
I'll put it to good use.
Fine...
いいだろう
It's all yours!
この体くれてやる
What?
I'm saying that I'll accept you!
受け入れると言ってるんだよ
普通拒絶しねぇか
Wouldn't people normally be against it?
オレはシンの皇帝になる男だ
I'm going to become the Emperor of Xing.
How do you expect me to do that if I can't even accept a few dozen people in my body?!
他人の２０や３０
受け入れるだけの
でかい懐がなくてどうする
I like decisive guys.
思い切りのいいヤツは好きだぜ
だが後悔すんなよ
But you'd better not regret it.
Regret?
後悔だと
If I return empty-handed, how could I possibly face my servant who cut her own arm off to save me?!
手ぶらで帰ったら
腕ぶった斬ってまで
尽くしてくれた臣下に
合わせる顔がないだろうが
I want power...
欲しいんだよ守るために
Absolute power that will help me protect and gain more!
手に入れるために絶対的な力が
I knew the risks from the beginning!
危険はもとより承知
その強欲さ気に入ったぜ
I like your greed.
Well then, show me how prepared you are!
どれお前の覚悟とやら
見せてもらおう
Ling?
リン
Huh? Oh, the guy who owned this body?
この体の持ち主のことか
Sorry, but now it belongs to me, Greed.
悪ぃなこの入れ物は
グリード様が もらっちまっ
Not Ling, but...
リンじゃなくて
Greed?!
グリードだと
You're that Greed?
お前 あのグリードなのか
What do you mean by "that" Greed?
「あの」ってどのだ
覚えてない
You don't remember?!
The one at Dublith...
ダブリスの
だからそりゃどこのグリードだ
Yeah, so what Greed are you talking about?
The Greed that came before you.
お前の前のグリードだ
Oh, I see.
なるほどってわけで
Well, as you can see,
オレはお前らの知ってるグリードとは別者だ
I'm a different Greed from the one you guys know.
リンは
What happened to Ling?
He was an interesting brat.
おもしろいガキだったぜ
He accepted me in a matter of seconds.
ヤツはオレをすんなり受け入れた
うそだあいつがそんな簡単に
No way! There's no way he's that easy to take control of!
乗っ取られるタマかよ
Answer me! Ling!
返事しろリンリン
Ling!!!
どうした
What?
No...
イヤだ
あの人 イヤだ
I don't like him...
He's a person, but at the same time, he's not!
人だけど人じゃない
確かに
You're right, a lot of these guys aren't human.
どれもこれも 人ではないな
シャオメイ
Shao May!
よかったよかった
I'm so glad to see you're safe!
心配したよ
Do you have any idea how worried I was?
Whoa, I don't really get it, but is this some tearful reunion?
なんか知らんが感動の再会
人造人間とグルではないようだな
It seems they aren't working together with the Homunculi.
鋼の錬金術師
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Huh? Where?
どこです
Where's Sir Edward?
エドワード様はどこ
Right there.
あれだ
I don't see him anywhere!
どこにもいないじゃないですか
だからあれだと言っている
I'm pointing right at him.
あの小柄なのが鋼の錬金術師だ
That small one is the Fullmetal Alchemist.
乙女の純情をもてあそんだわね
You toyed with my pure heart, you midget!
この飯粒男
んだとこの飯粒女が
Speak for yourself, midget!
PLACEHOLDER
What did you do to her, Brother?!
あれ食べ損ねたイシュヴァール人だ
He's the Ishbalan I didn't get to eat.
I didn't do a thing!
まつろわぬ民か
The disobedient people, huh...
確か破壊の錬金術師で
He's the one who uses destructive alchemy and continues to interfere with our plans, right?
事あるごとに邪魔をしてきたヤツだな
Take care of them, Gluttony.
片づけろグラトニー
ヤツは今術を使うことができない
He can't use alchemy right now.
はい
Okay!
何っ
What?!
I'll never forgive you!
許せません
You stepped all over a maiden's heart,
and on top of that, you kidnapped Shao May!
乙女心を踏みにじり
おまけにシャオメイまで誘拐して
みんな ひとまとめに
Divine punishment...
天誅
...for all of you!!!
ラッキー
Lucky!
We still can't use it!
やっぱ 発動しない
なんでだ
What gives?!
How can you two use alchemy here?
なぜここで術が使える
なんのことだ
What do you mean?
ほんとどうなってるんだろ
Seriously, what's going on?
どうしてスカーや あの子は
How can Scar and that little girl...
分かんねぇ分かんねぇけど
I have no idea.
No idea, but...
This could be our chance to fill them in.
状況打開のチャンスかもしんねぇ
スカー
Scar!
イシュヴァールの内乱の真実を教えてやる
I'll tell you the truth behind the Ishbal rebellion!
真実
The truth?
内乱のきっかけになった
The death of the child which became the trigger of the rebellion...
子供の射殺事件は
...was caused by him, disguised as a military officer!
そこのエンヴィーってヤツが
軍将校に化けてやったことだ
They're behind it all!
全部そいつらが仕組んだことだ
詳しく話を聞かせてもらわねば
It seems like I'll have to ask you to explain this in detail.
ならんようだな
答えろなぜ我らは
Answer me.
Why did my people have to fall?
滅ぼされねばならなかった
Depending on your answer, I'll send you to...
答えによっては
貴様らを神のいや
No.
I won't send you to God, where my fellow Ishbalans reside!
我らイシュヴァールの同胞が眠る
神のもとへは行かせん
Think of yourselves as undeserving of eternal rest or redemption!!!
安息も 救いも与えられぬものと思え
Wow, amazing!
すげぇ
人間のくせにやるなぁ
Not bad for a human.
グリード部外者を排除しろ
Greed, get rid of the intruders.
へいへい
Yeah, yeah...
I refuse to believe it, Ling!
オレは信じねぇぞリン
グリードだ
I'm Greed.
あれは確かヤオ家のリン
That's...
Could that be Ling from the Yao clan?
A little girl!
女の子
Soft body!
軟らかお肉
Hey you, how can you use alchemy?
お前なぜ錬金術が使える
Yes, you really are using it.
本当に発動している
人体破壊いや分解か
Human destruction...
No, decomposition.
あと一瞬逃げるのが
A second later, and I would have been...
遅かったらこちらが
スカーさん
Mr. Scar!
Shao May... Run...
シャオメイ逃げて
頂き
You're mine!
大丈夫
Are you okay?!
助けてくれなんて言った
I never asked you to save me...
何を甘いこと言ってんだ君は
What are you talking about?!
ヤツらは自分たちに
They're ruthless toward humans who are of no benefit to them.
無益な人間には容赦しない
Hurry up and get out of here!
早く逃げるんだ
多すぎだろこれ
There's way too many of them!
お前たち
You two didn't run away?!
逃げたのではなかったのか
スカーこの子を連れて
Scar, could you take this girl and get out of here?
地上に逃げられるか
オレを逃がすというのか
You're going to let me escape?
Even if I killed those doctors...
あの医者の娘にとって
敵であるこのオレを
Yeah, I want to beat the hell out of you.
殴り倒してやりたいさ
正直
To be honest, I don't even want to ask you for any favors.
お前なんかに頼むのはイヤだ
でも今は
But right now, it's more important to take this girl somewhere safe.
この子を逃がすのが先だ
貴様はどうする
What will you do?
ヤツらにとって
Apparently, my brother and I are important to them in some way.
僕たち兄弟は貴重な人材らしい
Even if we stay here, they won't kill us.
ここに残っても
殺されることはない
今のオレではその娘を守りながら
Right now, I won't be able to protect
that girl and escape from here at the same time.
ここを突破するのは 無理だ
それに
And I don't have the slightest intention of running away, either!
地上に逃げる気は毛頭ない
He decomposed water?!
水を分解 あっ
Geez, let me know before you do stuff like that!
もう
やるなら やるって言ってよ
ったく なんてムチャするんだ
How reckless!
水素に引火とはやってくれるな
Igniting hydrogen? That's clever of you.
どこだヤツはどこ行った
Where is he?
Where did he go?!
知らないよ
I don't know!
Gluttony, track him by scent!
グラトニーにおいで追え
もう再生力が残ってないのか
You're out of lives?!
死にすぎだ
You've died too much!
That was a nice kick.
なかなかいい蹴りだ
お前思ったより楽しめそうだ
I think this'll be more fun than I expected.
You stupid prince!
バカ皇子
しっかりしろ
Come back to your senses!
グリードだ
I'm Greed.
知るかリンに体を返せ
I don't care!
Give Ling back his body.
No can do!
できねぇ相談だ
スカしやがってこのアホが
What are you, an idiot?!
おめぇの国は
What are you going to do about your country?!
ランファンはどうすんだ
What about Lan Fan?!
PLACEHOLDER
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
痛てててっ
おやじ殿捕まえたぜ
Father! I got him.
Take him upstairs, where Wrath is.
上に
ラースのところに連れていけ
ったく
Seriously... Always screwing around with us...
余計なことばかりしてくれて
As long as you guys behave, we won't do a thing.
お前らがおとなしくしていれば
こっちも手を出さないんだよ
兄さん
Brother.
あいつ リンは中にいる
He...
Ling...
...is inside of him.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
朝日が昇るまで語り合ったね
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
夕陽が沈むまでつないだ手
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
こうやって明日も明後日も共に歩もう光と影
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
寂しげに見つめる街の中で
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
温もりはひとりじゃ見つからなくて
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
愛がこんなに強さになること
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
知ったんだ　キミに出逢えてはじめて
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
巡り巡ってもまたここで逢いたい
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
はぐれないようにこの手をつなぐんだ
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
一人じゃ眠れない　夢は見れないから
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
どんな不安も届かないところへ
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
星のない夜も照らし続けよう
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
何処までも行けるキミとなら
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
一人じゃ歩けない道も二人なら
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
鼻歌歌いながら歩けるんだ
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
キミがいれば幸せ
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
You used up your regeneration abilities, huh?
再生能力を使い果たしてしまったか
心配するな息子よ
Worry not, my son.
I will recreate you.
またつくり直してやる
記憶もそのままにな
With your memories, of course.
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
混とんの人間たちよ
Humans in chaos, struggle and writhe in agony.
苦しみもだえるがいい
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
それこそ生きている証し
Because that serves as proof that one is alive.
そして足掻いて後
And struggle and kneel before me.
我が前にひざまずけ
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第29話　「愚者の足掻き」
Episode 29, Struggle of the Fool.
手足を もがれた男は
Will the man who had his limbs twisted be able to stand again?
立ち上がることができるのか